<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cringepedia</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Cringepedia - The free encyclopedia but for cringe.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:40:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/cropped-cringepedia-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cringepedia</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>I asked the salary expectation of a candidate &#8211; So cringey</title>
		<link>/i-asked-the-salary-expectation-of-a-candidate-so-cringey/</link>
					<comments>/i-asked-the-salary-expectation-of-a-candidate-so-cringey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rebel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 02:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[HR supremacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linkedin Cringe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cringepedia.com/?p=526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cringe Excerpt I asked the salary expectation of a candidate.He told me that he is expecting 28K INR But I know the company gives me free hand for up to 35K in hand. He was a suitable and perfect match candidate, so without any further questions, I sent him an offer letter for 35K INR ... <a title="I asked the salary expectation of a candidate &#8211; So cringey" class="read-more" href="/i-asked-the-salary-expectation-of-a-candidate-so-cringey/" aria-label="More on I asked the salary expectation of a candidate &#8211; So cringey">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Cringe Excerpt</p><cite>I asked the salary expectation of a candidate.<br>He told me that he is expecting 28K INR<br><br>But I know the company gives me free hand for up to 35K in hand.<br><br>He was a suitable and perfect match candidate,<br><br>so without any further questions, I sent him an offer letter for 35K INR per month salary.<br><br>and he thanked me, I can see the happiness in his eyes.<br><br>Companies need to understand that If you pay the employee up to their expectation, they will deliver the result beyond employer expectations.<br><br>Share this so that HR can understand that they don&#8217;t pay salary from their pocket, so stop negotiating with candidates.<br><br>Agree?</cite></blockquote>



<h2>Origin</h2>



<p>The cringe seems to be originated from indian linkedin, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6779977272154828800/?updateEntityUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afs_feedUpdate%3A%28V2%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A6779977272154828800%29">here</a> the original poster claims he / she owns this cringe, so we assume he/she might be the patient zero</p>



<iframe src="https://www.linkedin.com/embed/feed/update/urn:li:share:6779977271810908160" allowfullscreen="" title="Embedded post" width="504" height="780" frameborder="0"></iframe>



<p>the post received 70,000 likes and 4,000 comments at the time of writing this article</p>



<h2>Mutations</h2>



<p>I have encountered several mutated versions of this cringe while surfing through linkedin</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>UAE version</p><cite>But I know the company gives me freehand for up to 6K AED in hand.<br><br>He was a suitable and perfect match candidate,<br><br>so without any further questions, I sent him an offer letter for a 6K AED per month salary.<br><br>and he thanked me, I can see the happiness in his eyes.<br><br>Companies need to understand that If you pay the employee up to their expectation, they will deliver the result beyond employer expectations.<br><br>Share this so that HR can understand that they don&#8217;t pay salary from their pocket, so stop negotiating with candidates.<br><br>Agree?</cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Pakistan version</p><cite>I asked the salary expectation of a candidate.<br>He told me that he is expecting 25K PKR<br><br>But being an HR, I know the company gives me freehand for up to 35K in hand. He was a suitable and perfect match candidate,<br><br>So without any further questions, I sent him an offer letter for 35K PKR per month salary. And he thanked me, I can see the happiness in his eyes.<br><br>Companies need to understand that If you pay the employee up to their expectation, they will deliver the result beyond employer expectations.<br><br>Share this so that HR can understand that they don&#8217;t pay salary from their pocket, so stop negotiating with candidates.<br><br>Agree?</cite></blockquote>



<h2>Why this cringe was probably created ?</h2>



<p>In the previous <a href="https://cringepedia.com/i-interviewed-a-candidate-through-skype-last-week/">article</a> i have mentioned HR&#8217;s aren&#8217;t worshipped enough for their service to the humanity, so my intuition is that, this is another fairy tale to demonstrate the importance of HR in the food chain. The message this cringe delievers is very simple</p>



<pre class="wp-block-verse">HR nOt bAd, HR gOoD,  HR hElP EmPloYeE</pre>



<p>lets keep the satire aside for a moment, if you willingly offer less salary for employee, then this is simply wage theft.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/i-asked-the-salary-expectation-of-a-candidate-so-cringey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I interviewed a candidate through skype last week.</title>
		<link>/i-interviewed-a-candidate-through-skype-last-week/</link>
					<comments>/i-interviewed-a-candidate-through-skype-last-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rebel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 02:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Linkedin Cringe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cringepedia.com/?p=510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every one would probably saw this cringe, this is circulated on linkedin, shared by HRs with reactions, this post will cover where this cringe was originated, how this cringe turned in to pandemic and how its still infecting new people everyday. Cringe excerpt I interviewed a candidate through Skype last week. During the call, I ... <a title="I interviewed a candidate through skype last week." class="read-more" href="/i-interviewed-a-candidate-through-skype-last-week/" aria-label="More on I interviewed a candidate through skype last week.">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Every one would probably saw this cringe, this is circulated on linkedin, shared by HRs with reactions, this post will cover where this cringe was originated, how this cringe turned in to pandemic and how its still infecting new people everyday.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>Cringe excerpt</strong></p><cite>I interviewed a candidate through Skype last week.<br><br>During the call, I heard kids crying in the background. His wife was also talking. The experience was too noisy.<br><br>The room he sat was clumsy. I was a bit disappointed.<br>I expected a more professional approach from him.<br><br>Somehow, he felt my disappointment while answering my questions and became unsettled. He stuttered several times.<br><br>After the interview, I told him I wasn&#8217;t impressed with how he presented himself.<br>He burst into tears, &#8220;I am sorry, Sir. I live in a room with my family. There&#8217;s nowhere they could have stayed.<br><br>&#8220;We used to live in a bigger apartment before I lost my job three years ago. This is all I can afford for now. I have failed my family. I know I have.&#8221; He said in tears.<br><br>I felt bad. I had no idea that he was going through a tough time.<br>I apologized and encouraged him not to feel heartbroken. After all, he&#8217;s trying his best.<br><br>Besides, he did well in the interview.<br>I gave him the contract and asked if he&#8217;d like to start next month.<br><br>He couldn&#8217;t believe it because he thought I was going to dismiss him.<br><br>He shouted out for joy, &#8220;Hey baby, I got the job.&#8221;<br>I saw his wife came to hug him.<br>I was moved.<br><br>I learned never to judge anyone. Life isn&#8217;t balanced. Let&#8217;s try to make someone smile.</cite></blockquote>



<h2>Origin</h2>



<p>Unfortunately due to linkedin&#8217;s superior search algorithm which can&#8217;t be perceived by the ordinary human brain made me not able to find the patient zero of this cringe before it turned in to pandemic, but neverthless i was able to find posts from 6 months back, so this assures the virus is still active and infecting people&#8217;s timeline.</p>



<h2>Why this cringe was probably constructed ?</h2>



<p>As we all know HR lies  in food chain between the god and humans, but we as humans aren&#8217;t worshipping them enough, we all think food chain looks like this</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="390" height="304" src="https://cringepedia.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/390px-Chesapeake_Waterbird_Food_Web.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-515" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/390px-Chesapeake_Waterbird_Food_Web.jpg 390w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/390px-Chesapeake_Waterbird_Food_Web-300x234.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 390px) 100vw, 390px" /></figure></div>



<p>but this is not true, no way it could be true, the food chain acutally looks like this</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>God -&gt; dinosaur -&gt; godzilla -&gt; kong -&gt; CEO -&gt; CTO -&gt; HR -&gt; you &amp; me</p><cite>a image explaining the actual food chain</cite></blockquote>



<p>HR&#8217;s arent respected enough for their service to the humanity, so this cringe is probably constructed to set things right, lets read between the lines to understand what it actually means</p>



<pre class="wp-block-verse">The room he sat was clumsy. I was a bit disappointed.</pre>



<p>As an HR interviewing a candidate would actually need full control of the house, you would probably need to provide him full access to your home to let him decide the location of the interview.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-verse">He burst into tears, "I am sorry, Sir. I live in a room with my family. There's nowhere they could have stayed.</pre>



<p>I am not sure why everyone linked in story has this part where candidate ends up in tears, but thats ok.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-verse">I gave him the contract and asked if he'd like to start next month.</pre>



<p>The happy ending part for every linkedin story, this is it</p>



<pre class="wp-block-verse">I learned never to judge anyone. Life isn't balanced. Let's try to make someone smile.</pre>



<p>This roughly translates to i hired a candidate and i am great, all hail lord megatron.</p>



<h2>Spread</h2>



<p>This cringe spread at a very rapid rate, it even ended up in reddit copy pasta</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-reddit wp-block-embed-reddit"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
    <blockquote class="reddit-card" >      <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/copypasta/comments/jkc7y3/i_interviewed_a_candidate_through_skype_last_week/?ref_source=embed&amp;ref=share">I interviewed a candidate through Skype last week.</a> from      <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/copypasta/">copypasta</a>    </blockquote>    <script async src="https://embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Thats it,  i dont have any other content to write on this topic right now. i will be back with a new cringey post, choose any one of these topics and make a comment</p>



<ul><li>Why crying at workplace might actually be a good sign</li><li>Do these 5 thing to simp for your company</li><li>why you should work 18+ hrs a day</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/i-interviewed-a-candidate-through-skype-last-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
